Anil Ozsoy

Dusseldorf/Germany +491724368167 anilozsoy@gmail.com

Frontend Developer

An experienced professional with a background in UX design and a successful transition to frontend development. Proficient in HTML, CSS, JavaScript/TypeScript, React, Node.js, Express.js, and MongoDB. Optimised user experiences, resulting in a notable 24% increase in engagement over 2 years, a 12% increase in satisfaction, and a 15% improvement in project efficiency. Seeking new opportunities in frontend development or related roles.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Freelance Developer

Düsseldorf/Germany | 03/2023 - Present

trivago

Senior Experience Designer

Düsseldorf/Germany | 05/2019 - 02/2023

Jotform

Experience Designer - Team Lead Ankara/Turkey | 04/2017 - 05/2019

ICterra Communication Tech. Frontend Developer / UX Designer

Ankara/Turkey | 12/2015 - 04/2017

- Mastered Redux Toolkit and TypeScript in 2 months post-bootcamp, Developed two web applications.
- Established an backend infrastructure utilizing Node.js and Express.js resulting in a significant decrease in development time by 25% in just 2 weeks.
- Designed and launched trivago Business Studio, delivering 24% user engagement and 20% conversion rate increase.
- Created and documented a robust design system for all trivago Business Studio products, improving consistency and usability across mobile and web devices over 3 years.
- Led team of 6 in integrating new form type into JotForm, driving a 32% user engagement rise in 2 years.
- Created engaging user interfaces resulting in a 20% rise in user interaction within 2 years.
- Designed and integrated 2 responsive web apps using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript, resulting in a 20% traffic boost and 12% higher user satisfaction in 2 years.
- Collaborated on Wacom & MontBlanc apps, delivering designs and enhancing UI/UX efficiency by 25% within 6 months, resulting in a 10% increase in user engagement.

EDUCATION

Full Stack Web Development Bootcamp

Ironhack

BA in Graphic Design

Bilkent University

Attained proficiency in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, Express.js, MongoDB, and Node.js through the successful completion of a comprehensive full-time web development bootcamp.

PROJECTS

Small Fresh full stack e-commerce website

 Built a full-stack e-commerce website using Tailwind CSS, React, Node.js, Express.js, MongoDB, and Git. Incorporated product listing, filtering, search, and shopping cart features within 6 weeks.

Feedback management platform

 Developed a responsive web platform using HTML, SCSS, React, and Git. Integrated sorting, filtering, commenting, and threaded replies within three weeks. Coded a responsive online job board using HTML, SCSS, React, and Implemented filtering options and provided detailed job information for seamless job application.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- JavaScript
- TypeScript
- JQuery
- ExpressJS
- ReactJS
- NextJS
-
- ReduxJS
- NodeJS
- MongoDB
- RESTApi Development

• HTML/HTML5

• CSS/CSS3

SASS

· Saas

Jira

Tailwind

Bootstrap

Wordpress

Figma/Sketch

Version Control(Git)

SKILLS

- Clearly convey design concepts to non-technical stakeholders and collaborate for seamless project execution.
- Articulate design concepts to non-technical stakeholders and collaborate for smooth project execution.
- Quickly adapt to evolving requirements, learn new web technologies, and deliver high-quality solutions.
- Analyze complex problems, identify creative solutions, and optimize user interfaces.
- Collaborate within cross-functional teams, fostering a positive and productive work environment.